in this video I'm gonna show you how you
can track down the commit that
introduced to bugs using git's bisect tool
I have a simple webpage running locally
that represents our application and when I load
the page you'll see that we get this
alert message that alert message
represents the bug that we need to track
down git bisect helps you track down
when a bug was introduced by checking
out commits for you and accepting
feedback basically you tell the tool if
a commit is good meaning no bug or bad meaning
the bug is present it narrows it down to the
earliest commit where the bug is present
so let's see it in action in order for
this to work will need to find a commit
that does not have the bug in our case
will start at the initial commit but in
the real world you probably go back to a
specific release and confirm that the
bugs and present and start from there
I going to use git log and go to my initial
commit and I'll grab the hash for this
commit and I want to tell git to run bisect
so I'll type in git bisect start
and it'll look like nothing's happened but it has
started the process so the next piece of
information we need to give it is our
known good commit to do that by
running git bisect good followed by the
hash for a known good commit and we're
also gonna run get bisect bad bad will
take a commit hash as well but if you
don't pass it one is just going to
assume the current commit so we're
basically saying that we know the
initial commit was good we know the
current committee as bad
help us track down the one that
introduced the bug and as soon as we run
that it's gonna check out a commit in
between our two commits so at this point
we have this commit checked out and we're going
to refresh our page and do whatever it
is that we have to do to test our
application cases just reloading the web
page we do that we'll see that it's in a
different state but we don't have our
bug so we're gonna give git bisect some
feedback by saying git bisect good
and its gonna check out another commit
so basically use that feedback to know
where it stands so go back in we'll
retest our application and we have a bug
here so we're getting this modal alert
message and we don't want that
so I'm gonna go back and I'm gonna let git
bisect know that that was bad so i'll check out
another commit we'll run our test again
and it's bad so we'll let it know get bisect bad
it'll check out another commit no bug there
so we'll give it the good feedback
it'll check out another commit we'll test
again no bug we repeat the cycle no bug
again and when it's done it's gonna give
us a commit who authored that commit
when they did it and the files that were
changed when we're done we've gotten
information we need we run a git status
we'll see that we're in a Detached head
state cause it has that last commit checked
out so we can just call git bisect
reset and it will check out our current
branch and put us back in a good working state